[
    {
        "question": "1. A ray of light which strikes a glass slab from air at normal incidence passes through the slab", 
        "optionA": "undeviated and undisplaced at a lower speed", 
        "optionB": "deviated and undisplaced at a lower speed", 
        "optionC": "deviated and displaced at a lower speed",
        "optionD": "undeviated and displaced at a faster speed",
        "answer": "undeviated and undisplaced at a lower speed"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. A short chain is usually attached to the back of a petrol tanker and trailing behind it so that the", 
        "optionA": "petrol tanker is balanced on the road", 
        "optionB": "heat generated by friction in the engine can be conducted to the earth", 
        "optionC": "charges generated by friction in the tanker are conducted to the earth",
        "optionD": "chain can produce sound in resonance with the noise from the tanker's engine",
        "answer": "charges generated by friction in the tanker are conducted to the earth" 
    },
    {
        "question": "3. At constant pressure, the density of a fixed mass of gas is",
        "optionA": "constant with temperature",
        "optionB": "proportional to its volume",
        "optionC": "inversely proportional to its temperature",
        "optionD": "independent of its volume",
        "answer": "inversely proportional to its temperature"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. A household refrigerator is rated 200 watts. If electricity costs 5k per kWh, what is the cost of operating it in 20 days?",
        "optionA": "N480.00",
        "optionB": "N48.00",
        "optionC": "N4800.00",
        "optionD": "N4.80",
        "answer": "N4.80"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. The absolute refractive indices of glass and water are 3/2 and 4/3 respectively. The refractive index at the interface when a ray travels from water to glass is",
        "optionA": "1/2 ",
        "optionB": "8/9",
        "optionC": "9/8",
        "optionD": "17/12",
        "answer": "9/8"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. A projectile is fired from the ground level with a velocity of 300ms-1 at an angle of a 30 degrees to the horizontal. Calculate the time taken to reach the maximum height? g = 10ms-2",
        "optionA": "30s",
        "optionB": "20s",
        "optionC": "25s",
        "optionD": "15s",
        "answer": "15s"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. A positively charged rod X is brought near an uncharged metal sphere Y and is then touched by a finger with X still in place. When the finger is removed, the result is that Y has",
        "optionA": "no charge and a zero potential",
        "optionB": "a negative charge and a negative potential",
        "optionC": "a negative charge and a positive potential",
        "optionD": "a positive charge and a zero potential",
        "answer": "a negative charge and a negative potential"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Musical instruments playing the same note can be distinguished from one another owing to the difference in their",
        "optionA": "pitch",
        "optionB": "intensity",
        "optionC": " loudness",
        "optionD": "quality",
        "answer": "pitch"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. A ball of mass 800g moving horizontally with a speed of 5m/s hits a vertical wall and rebounds with the same speed. The impulse experienced by the ball is?",
        "optionA": "1kgm",
        "optionB": "2kgm/s",
        "optionC": "4kgm/s",
        "optionD": "8kgm/s",
        "answer": "8kgm/s"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. An object is placed 20cm from a concave mirror of focal length 10cm. The linear magnification of the image produced is?",
        "optionA": "0",
        "optionB": "1/2",
        "optionC": "1",
        "optionD": "2",
        "answer": "1"
    }
]